const qBank = [
    {
        id: 1,
        question: "A substance is defined as any *",
        options: ["over-the-counter prescription drug.", "drug that has psychedelic effects.", "product that could potentially create an addiction.", "natural or synthesized product that has psychoactive effects"],
        answer: "natural or synthesized product that has psychoactive effects",
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        question: "Identify the physiological effect of nicotine.",
        options: ["It resembles a fight-or-flight response", "It reduces stress and anxiety", "It suppresses several biochemicals including dopamine and norepinephrine.", "It reduces the craving to smoke more."],
        answer: "It resembles a fight-or-flight response",
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        question: "Korsakoff’s syndrome is caused by damage to ___________ and is classified as a(n)__________",
        options: ["vertebrae; dementia", "adrenal glands; delirium", "carotid artery; medical disease", "thalamus; amnesic disorder"],
        answer: "thalamus; amnesic disorder"
    },
    {
        id: 4,
        question: "The person diagnosed with Alzheimer's disease at age 45 would be considered to have an____________.",
        options: ["premature-onset type", "early-onset type", "late-onset type", "post-onset tie"],
        answer: "early-onset type"
    },
    {
        id: 5,
        question: "Which of the following is the difference between 'normal' memory lapses and dementia?",
        options: ["with normal memory lapses, the person is much older than someone with dementia", "in dementia, the memory does not return spontaneously, and may not respond to memory cues", "with normal memory lapses, the person is probably entering the onset of dementia", "in dementia, the memory loss is associated to psychological effects of stress"],
        answer: "in dementia, the memory does not return spontaneously, and may not respond to memory cues"
    },
    {
        id: 6,
        question: "A loss of interest in everything in life is called _____.",
        options: ["depression", "anxiety", "anhedonia", "dissociation"],
        answer: "anhedonia",
    },
    {
        id: 7,
        question: "If a person experiences depressed mood or loss of interest in usual activities, and at least four other depressive symptoms for at least two weeks, and these symptoms are severe enough to interfere with the person's ability to function in everyday life, the person meets the criteria for _____.",
        options: ["adjustment disorder", "major depressive disorder", "schizophrenia", "bipolar disorder"],
        answer: "major depressive disorder",
    },
    {
        id: 8,
        question: "Which of the following is a negative symptom of schizophrenia?",
        options: ["Catatonia", "Derailment", "Avolition", "Delusions"],
        answer: "Avolition",
    },
    {
        id: 9,
        question: "Renz believes that he is being followed but shows no other psychotic symptoms. Other than his delusion, he does not act oddly or have difficulty functioning. He is most likely to be diagnosed with _____.",
        options: ["delusional disorder", "schizophrenia spectrum disorder", "brief psychotic disorder", "schizophreniform disorder"],
        answer: "delusional disorder",
    },
    {
        id: 10,
        question: "Under the DSM-5 criteria, which of the following pathological personality traits is associated with avoidant personality disorder?",
        options: ["Psychoticism", "Detachment", "Disinhibition", "Antagonism"],
        answer: "Detachment",
    },
    {
        id: 11,
        question: "Which term refers to the consistency of measurement across time?",
        options: ["Reliability", "Validity", "Accuracy", "Predictability"],
        answer: "Reliability",
    },
    {
        id: 12,
        question: "The process of verifying that there is a performance deficiency and determining if such deficiency should be corrected through training or through some other means is called _____.",
        options: ["needs analysis", "task analysis", "performance analysis", "training strategy", "development planning"],
        answer: "performance analysis",
    },
    {
        id: 13,
        question: "When an interview is used to predict future job performance on the basis of an applicant’s oral responses to oral inquiries, it is called a(n) _____ interview.",
        options: ["selection", "appraisal", "exit", "preview", "structured"],
        answer: "selection",
    },
    {
        id: 14,
        question: "According to Herzberg, ________ needs produce job satisfaction, and ________ needs produce job dissatisfaction.",
        options: ["motivator; hygiene", "hygiene; motivator", "external; internal", "satisfier; motivator"],
        answer: "motivator; hygiene",
    },
    {
        id: 15,
        question: "The psychological and physical reaction to certain events or situations is called:",
        options: ["Stress", "Strain", "Stressors", "Eustress"],
        answer: "Stress",
    },
    {
        id: 16,
        question: "The field of study dealing with the health effects of job stress and other aspects of employee well-being is known as ___________.",
        options: ["organizational health psychology", "occupational health psychology", "organizational Behavior", "social psychology"],
        answer: "occupational health psychology",
    },
    {
        id: 17,
        question: "Depersonalization is a characteristic of __________.",
        options: ["Workaholism", "Burnout", "Mass psychogenic illness", "Locus of control"],
        answer: "Burnout",
    },
    {
        id: 18,
        question: "In the I-P-O model of teams, the P stands for",
        options: ["person", "process", "performance", "project"],
        answer: "process",
    },
    {
        id: 19,
        question: "___________ results when job responsibilities are unstructured or poorly defined.",
        options: ["Role conflict", "Work underload", "Work overload", "Role ambiguity"],
        answer: "Role ambiguity",
    },
    {
        id: 20,
        question: "Goals that are __________ to attain are better motivators than goals that are ___________ to attain.",
        options: ["difficult; easy", "easy; difficult", "slightly difficult; moderately difficult", "no difference"],
        answer: "difficult; easy",
    },
    {
        id: 21,
        question: "A Pearson r correlation coefficient describes the ______ and the ______ of a linear relationship between two interval scale or ratio scale variables.",
        options: ["level; amount", "similarity; importance", "direction; strength", "variability; significance"],
        answer: "direction; strength",
    },
    {
        id: 22,
        question: "The term class intervals is best associated with",
        options: ["A socioeconomic status of a sample of test taker", "A frequency distribution of test taker scores", "A grouped frequency distribution of test takers scores", "Measures of central tendency"],
        answer: "A grouped frequency distribution of test takers scores",
    },
    {
        id: 23,
        question: "Credit for devising the first successful psychological testing the modern era is usually given to",
        options: ["Francis Galton", "Alfred Binet", "Wilhelm Wundt", "James McKeen Cattell"],
        answer: "Alfred Binet",
    },
    {
        id: 24,
        question: "He coined the term mental tests",
        options: ["James Mckeen Cattell", "Raymond Cattell", "Lewis Terman", "Alfred Binet"],
        answer: "James Mckeen Cattell",
    },
    {
        id: 25,
        question: "Correction in which expects an  examinee’s degree of psychological defensiveness is perhaps the most sophisticated of the _____________ scale",
        options: ["Clinical", "Testing", "Reliability", "Validity"],
        answer: "Testing",
    },
    {
        id: 26,
        question: "Which of the following is a projective technique?",
        options: ["Block Design", "Bender test", "Army Beta", "NEO-PI"],
        answer: "Bender test",
    },
    {
        id: 27,
        question: "Equal to the square root of the averaged squared deviation about the mean, this statistics is called",
        options: ["The range", "The standard deviation", "The average deviation", "The semi-interquartile"],
        answer: "The standard deviation",
    },
    {
        id: 28,
        question: "Which is a criterion- referenced test?",
        options: ["The final competition in the Your Face Sounds Familiar", "An examination for entry in a faculty union", "A teacher made midterm examination scored on a curve", "None of the above"],
        answer: "An examination for entry in a faculty union",
    },
    {
        id: 29,
        question: "The theoretical basis for the Edwards Personal preference schedule is",
        options: ["The socio-cultural perspective proposed by Horney", "The needs system proposed by Murray", "The factor analytic approach by Cattell", "The psychodynamic approach by Freud"],
        answer: "The needs system proposed by Murray",
    },
    {
        id: 30,
        question: "A person’s accumulation of stored information, called _____ intelligence, generally ______ with age.",
        options: ["Fluid; decreases", "Fluid; increases", "Crystallized; increase", "Crystallized; decrease"],
        answer: "Crystallized; increase",
    },
    {
        id: 31,
        question: "The _____ classifies people according to Carl Jung’s personality types",
        options: ["Myer’s Briggs Type Indicator", "MMPI", "Locus of Control Scale", "TAT"],
        answer: "Myer’s Briggs Type Indicator",
    },
    {
        id: 32,
        question: "Every time two year old Kati is given a bath, she plays with her genital area. If her parents punish her, she is likely to experience frustration, which of the following can explain if said child becomes sexually preoccupied?",
        options: ["Freud", "Skinner", "Bandura", "Ericson"],
        answer: "Freud",
    },
    {
        id: 33,
        question: "The actualizing tendency and self-concept are to _______ as reciprocal determination and self-efficacy are to ______.",
        options: ["Abraham Maslow; Hans Eysenck", "Alfred Adler; Albert Bandura", "Raymond Cattell; Carl Jung", "Carl Rogers; Albert Bandura"],
        answer: "Carl Rogers; Albert Bandura",
    },
    {
        id: 34,
        question: "During the meeting, an employee just went along to the majority decision. This best reflects which of the following?",
        options: ["pakikitungo", "Hiya", "pakikibagay", "pakikisama"],
        answer: "pakikisama",
    },
    {
        id: 35,
        question: " __________ theory maximized and _________ theory minimized the role of the unconscious",
        options: ["Trait; humanistic", "Psychoanalytic; behaviorist", "Psychoanalytic; humanistic", "Trait; behaviorist"],
        answer: "Psychoanalytic; humanistic",
    },
    {
        id: 36,
        question: "A psychiatrist who explains pathological behavior as a conflict between underlying psychological forces is using the ________ model.",
        options: ["psychoanalytical", "behavioral", "medical", "humanistic"],
        answer: "psychoanalytical",
    },
    {
        id: 37,
        question: "The _________ contains material of which you may be unaware but can easily be brought to awareness.",
        options: ["subconscious", "preconscious", "unconscious", "conscious"],
        answer: "preconscious",
    },
    {
        id: 38,
        question: "A person who is high in which the following traits would be most likely to be psychologically and physically healthy?",
        options: ["neuroticism, hostility, pessimism", "extraversion, hardiness, optimism", "conscientiousness, hostility, extraversion", "agreeableness, pessimism, introversion"],
        answer: "extraversion, hardiness, optimism",
    },
    {
        id: 39,
        question: "Jung believed that there are basic universal concepts in all people regardless of culture called",
        options: ["persona.", "collective consciousness.", "archetypes.", "mandalas"],
        answer: "archetypes.",
    },
    {
        id: 40,
        question: "Horney believed that a competitive and hostile society encourages.",
        options: ["hatred.", "love.", "isolation.", "superiority and success."],
        answer: "isolation.",
    },
    {
        id: 41,
        question: "Which personality theories attempt to explain behavior by focusing on the inner workings of the personality including internal conflicts?",
        options: ["trait", "behavioristic", "psychodynamic", "humanistic"],
        answer: "psychodynamic",
    },
    {
        id: 42,
        question: "The variable of interest, or what we design experiments to assess",
        options: ["Hypothesis", "Dependent variable", "Extraneous variable", "Divergent validity"],
        answer: "Dependent variable",
    },
    {
        id: 43,
        question: "The variable of interest, or what we design experiments to assess",
        options: ["Hypothesis", "Dependent variable", "Extraneous variable", "Divergent validity"],
        answer: "Dependent variable",
    },
    {
        id: 44,
        question: "The extent to which two independent forms of a test are equivalent measures of the same construct; sometimes called equivalent forms reliability or a coefficient of equivalence",
        options: ["Statistic", "Test-retest reliability", "Parallel forms reliability", "Internal consistency"],
        answer: "Parallel forms reliability",
    },
    {
        id: 45,
        question: "An approach to science in which we start with theory and propositions and then collect data to test these propositions - working from theory to data",
        options: ["Deduction", "Archival Research", "Theory", "Dependent Variable"],
        answer: "Deduction",
    },
    {
        id: 46,
        question: "The consistency or stability of a measure",
        options: ["Reliability", "Statistic", "Case Studies", "Content Validity"],
        answer: "Reliability",
    },
    {
        id: 47,
        question: "The degree to which a test or predictor covers a representative sample of the quality being assessed",
        options: ["Statistic", "Content validity", "Predictive validity", "Reliability"],
        answer: "Content validity",
    },
    {
        id: 48,
        question: "The extent to which the results obtained in an experiment generalizes to other people, settings, and times",
        options: ["Reliability", "External validity", "Internal validity", "Construct validity"],
        answer: "External validity",
    },
    {
        id: 49,
        question: "A mathematically based distributions depicted as a bell-shaped curve, in which most of the observations cluster around the mean and there are few extreme observations",
        options: ["Variance", "Standard deviation", "Normal distribution", "Reliability"],
        answer: "Normal distribution",
    },
    {
        id: 50,
        question: "The degree to which a measue of the construct in which we are interested is not related to measures of other, dissimilar constructs",
        options: ["Convergent validity", "Divergent validity", "Predictive validity", "Concurrent validity"],
        answer: "Divergent validity",
    },
    {
        id: 51,
        question: "A measure of dispersion that is calculated as the square root of the variance",
        options: ["Variance", "Standard deviation", "Mode", "Range"],
        answer: "Standard deviation",
    },
    {
        id: 52,
        question: "A data collection technique that involves selecting a sample of respondents and administration some type of questionnaire",
        options: ["Archival Research", "Construct Validity", "Surveys", "Case Studies"],
        answer: "Surveys",
    },
    {
        id: 53,
        question: "Examinations of a single individual, group, company, or society",
        options: ["Case studies", "Archival research", "Correlation coefficient", "Surveys"],
        answer: "Case studies",
    },
    {
        id: 54,
        question: "An efficient device for summarizing in a single number the values, characteristics, or scores describing a series of cases",
        options: ["Statistic", "Variance", "Parameter", "Dependent Variable"],
        answer: "Statistic",
    },
    {
        id: 55,
        question: "The systematic control, variation, or application of independent variable to different groups of participants",
        options: ["Distraction", "Persuasion", "Placation", "Manipulation"],
        answer: "Manipulation",
    },
    {
        id: 56,
        question: "A conclusion, drawn from research data, about the likelihood of a causal relationship between two variables",
        options: ["Science", "Casual inference", "Statistic", "External validity"],
        answer: "Casual inference",
    },
    {
        id: 57,
        question: "The extent to which multiple raters or judges agree on ratings made about a particular person, thing, or behavior",
        options: ["Parallel forms reliability", "Interrater reliability", "Science", "Internal validity"],
        answer: "Interrater reliability",
    },
    {
        id: 58,
        question: "A variable that is systematically manipulated by the experimenter or, at the least, measured by the experimenter as an antecedent to other variables.",
        options: ["Content validity", "Extraneous variable", "Independent variable", "Hypothesis"],
        answer: "Independent variable",
    },
    {
        id: 59,
        question: "A set of interrelated constructs (concepts), definitions, and propositions that present a systematic view of a phenomenon by specifying relations among variables, with the purpose of explaining and predicting the phenomenon",
        options: ["Theory", "Science", "Independent variable", "Hypothesis"],
        answer: "Theory",
    },
    {
        id: 60,
        question: "The procedure by which research participants, once selected, are assigned to conditions such that each one has an equally likely chance of being assigned to each condition",
        options: ["Independent variable", "Induction", "Informed consent", "Random assignment"],
        answer: "Random assignment",
    },
    {
        id: 61,
        question: "A technique that allows researchers to obtain repeated real-time reports of phenomena such as methods and emotions through use of technology such as personal digital assistants (PDA's)",
        options: ["Deduction", "External validity", "Experience sampling methodology (ESM)", "Measurement"],
        answer: "Experience sampling methodology (ESM)",
    },
    {
        id: 62,
        question: "A technique that allows researchers to obtain repeated real-time reports of phenomena such as methods and emotions through use of technology such as personal digital assistants (PDA's)",
        options: ["Deduction", "External validity", "Experience sampling methodology (ESM)", "Measurement"],
        answer: "Experience sampling methodology (ESM)",
    },
    //For answer
    {
        id: 63,
        question: "Which of these definitions applies to ALL types of abnormal behaviour?",
        options: ["Abnormal behaviour occurs infrequently.", "Abnormal behaviour is odd or strange.", "Abnormal behaviour is characterized by suffering.", "Abnormal behaviour causes impairment in the person’s life."],
        answer: "Abnormal behaviour causes impairment in the person’s life.",
    },
    {
        id: 64,
        question: "Comorbidity refers to:",
        options: ["The frequency of mental illness", "Two or more causes of death indicated for patients", "The occurrence of 2 or more disorders at the same time", "The degree of suffering of mentally ill patients", "The frequency of family-related mental illness" ],
        answer: "The occurrence of 2 or more disorders at the same time",
    },
    {
        id: 65,
        question: "In terms of the early parent–child relationship in the development of mental illness, which of the following accurately explains how contemporary psychodynamic models differ to that of Freud?",
        options: ["Contemporary models focus more on interpersonal relationships than on intrapsychic conflict.", "Contemporary models focus on the unconscious internal desires and motivations of the child.", "Contemporary models focus on how the child negotiates his/her unconscious internal desires and motivations as s/he progresses through the early relationship with his/her parents.", "None of the above." ],
        answer: "Contemporary models focus more on interpersonal relationships than on intrapsychic conflict.",
    },
    {
        id: 66,
        question: "Biological models of mental disorders explain mental illness as resulting from which of the following factors?",
        options: ["Biochemical imbalance", "Genetic predisposition", "Familial transmission", "Brain defects", "All of the above"],
        answer: "All of the above",
    },
    {
        id: 67,
        question: "Which model explains that psychological disorders develop when people with some vulnerability to mental illness experience proximal stressors?",
        options: ["Diathesis-stress model", "Attachment model", "Psychodynamic model", "Cognitive-behavioral model", "Parent-stressor model"],
        answer: "Diathesis-stress model"
    },
    {
        id: 68,
        question: "Which are true of the diathesis–stress model of mental illness? Please identify all correct answers.\n\nWhen an enduring vulnerability factor in a person is coupled with a recent stressor, it results in psychological disorder.\nOnly one of the diathesis or stressor needs to be present for symptoms of the psychological disorder to occur.\nBoth the diathesis and the stressor must be present to lead to symptoms of the psychological disorder.\nDiatheses and stressors have specific definitions.",
        options: ["1 & 4", "1 & 3", "2 & 3", "2 & 4"],
        answer: "1 & 3"
    },
    {
        id: 69,
        question: "We know that a distinction is made between positive and negative symptoms of schizophrenia. What is the difference between these symptoms?",
        options: ["Negative symptoms indicate the presence of something normal, and positive symptoms indicate the absence of something unusual.", "Positive symptoms indicate the presence of something normal, and negative symptoms indicate the absence of something unusual.", "Negative symptoms indicate the presence of something unusual, and positive symptoms indicate the absence of something normal.", "Positive symptoms indicate the presence of something unusual, and negative symptoms indicate the absence of something normal."],
        answer: "Positive symptoms indicate the presence of something unusual, and negative symptoms indicate the absence of something normal."
    },
    {
        id: 70,
        question: "Which one of the following types of factors has been found to be the most likely cause of schizophrenia?",
        options: ["Social factors", "Genetic factors", "Psychological factors", "Environmental factors"],
        answer: "Genetic factors"
    },
    {
        id: 71,
        question: "Which of the following is not a risk factor for suicide?",
        options: ["Depression", "Substance abuse", "Stressful events", "Social support", "A plan to commit suicide"],
        answer: "Social support"
    },
    {
        id: 72,
        question: "Which psychological disorder is characterized by hallucinations, delusions, using bizarre language and inappropriate affect?",
        options: ["Depression", "Schizophrenia", "Obsessive-compulsive disorder", "Eating disorders", "Generalized anxiety disorder"],
        answer: "Schizophrenia"
    },
    {
        id: 73,
        question: "Symptoms of major depressive disorder might include:\n\nSpecific phobias.\nLosing interest or pleasure in things that you usually enjoy.\nChanges in appetite.\nAn excessively euphoric mood.",
        options: ["1 & 2", "3 & 4", "2 & 3", "1 & 4"],
        answer: "2 & 3"
    },
    {
        id: 74,
        question: "Identify the accurate assertion from those given below, in relation to the course of major depressive disorder:",
        options: ["Most people with major depressive disorder experience only isolated episodes of depression.", "Depression is a disorder of adulthood and does not affect children.", "Major depressive disorder follows a recurrent course.", "Early onset of major depressive disorder predicts a better course of depression over time."],
        answer: "Major depressive disorder follows a recurrent course."
    },
    {
        id: 75,
        question: "Which of the following is a characteristic of people with social phobia?",
        options: ["Only very rarely does their condition lead to significant social isolation.", "Their condition can range from relatively mild to extremely pervasive.", "They are afraid of other people.", "They are afraid of social situations."],
        answer: "Their condition can range from relatively mild to extremely pervasive."
    },
    {
        id: 76,
        question: "Which of the following do we know to be the case, in terms of the causes of anxiety disorders and factors affecting their course?",
        options: ["The extent of heritability is the same for all anxiety disorders.", "People prone to anxiety disorders are born with behavioural exhibition.", "All anxiety disorders have the same range of biological causes.", "Cognitive, behavioural and life stress factors affect risk for anxiety disorders."],
        answer: "Cognitive, behavioural and life stress factors affect risk for anxiety disorders."
    },
    {
        id: 77,
        question: "Which of the following symptoms do anorexia nervosa and bulimia nervosa have in common?",
        options: ["Distorted body image", "Intense fear of being fat", "Sense of self revolves around body and weight", "Eating regulated by psychological and not physical processes", "All of the above"],
        answer: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        id: 78,
        question: "The tension-reduction hypothesis attempts to explain the development of which type of mental disorder?",
        options: ["Schizophrenia", "Eating disorders", "Substance abuse", "Major depression", "Bipolar disorder"],
        answer: "Substance abuse"
    },
    {
        id: 79,
        question: "Common impairments of a substance abuser might include:",
        options: ["Failure to fulfil major role obligations.", "Legal problems.", "Both (a) and (b).", "Neither (a) nor (b)"],
        answer: "Both (a) and (b)."
    },
    {
        id: 80,
        question: "Which type of mental illness is most resistant to change?",
        options: ["Personality disorders", "Eating disorders", "Anxiety disorders", "Schizophrenia", "Affective disorders"],
        answer: "Personality disorders"
    },
    {
        id: 81,
        question: "According to research, children who are behaviorally inhibited are shy, quiet, fearful, socially avoidant and have high levels of physiological arousal. These children are most likely to develop which type of psychological disorders?",
        options: ["Psychotic disorders", "Anxiety disorders", "Eating disorders", "Substance abuse disorders", "None of the above"],
        answer: "Anxiety disorders"
    },
    {
        id: 82,
        question: "For which type of mental illness is there considerable evidence that it is caused by biological factors and little to no evidence that it is caused by psychosocial factors?",
        options: ["Bipolar disorder", "Panic disorder", "Bulimia nervosa", "Schizophrenia", "(a) and (d)"],
        answer: "(a) and (d)"
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "question": "One of these statements about job selection is FALSE. But which one?",
        "options": ["Job selection is based on the premise that there are differences between people which can be identified.", "Job selection is based on the premise that there are differences between people that have an impact on how effective people are in a particular job.", "Psychologists are beginning to come to the fore in terms of developing and using personnel selection methods.", "Failure to achieve a fit between the person and the organization can lead to a feeling of low esteem on the part of the employee."],
        "answer": "Psychologists are beginning to come to the fore in terms of developing and using personnel selection methods."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "question": "The process by which members of a society are taught how to behave and feel by influential members of that society is referred to as ________________.",
        "options": ["Role ambiguity", "Socialization", "Hawthorne effect", "Social roles", "Normative influence"],
        "answer": "Socialization"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "question": "Once you have started work for an organization, through socialization and training it will seek to shape you to fit in and to contribute to achieving its goals. But which of the following is NOT true of socialization?",
        "options": ["Socialization is the process by which members of a society are taught how to behave and feel by influential members of that society.", "Socialization can occur in a country, organization or even in a family.", "In the past, socialization theory and research has concentrated on the development of adults, but more recently, it has become clear that children are also socialized.", "When employees start work, they learn to align their work values with those of the organization."],
        "answer": "In the past, socialization theory and research has concentrated on the development of adults, but more recently, it has become clear that children are also socialized."
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "question": "All of the following are examples of selection procedures used by organizations to match people with jobs except for ___________.",
        "options": ["Work-sample tests", "Biodata", "Psychometric tests", "Work load tests", "Interviews"],
        "answer": "Work load tests"
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "question": "Which one of these statements about training is FALSE?",
        "options": ["There was very little change in work environments over the last quarter of the twentieth century.", "Most people at work need continual training to update their skills.", "The approach to training in many organizations is often reactive.", "Psychologists have much to offer organizations in making training effective."],
        "answer": "There was very little change in work environments over the last quarter of the twentieth century."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "question": "Of these assertions about leadership styles, one is correct. Which one is it?",
        "options": ["Organizational psychologists have recently changed their focus on leadership from personality to environmental factors and back to personality again.", "Charismatic leadership and transformational leadership are opposing leadership styles.", "Charismatic leaders exercise intense influence over others and have high expectations of their followers’ performance, but usually communicate their goals and visions in a confused way.", "Some studies suggest that transformational leaders inspire dissatisfaction amongst their employees, resulting in lower productivity."],
        "answer": "Organizational psychologists have recently changed their focus on leadership from personality to environmental factors and back to personality again."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "question": "People’s temple cult leader, Reverend Jim Jones, persuaded his followers to feed a poison-laced drink to their children and then drink it themselves, and nearly 1,000 people died. This is an example of the negative influence of _______________.",
        "options": ["Social roles", "Transactional leadership", "Transformational leadership", "Hawthorne effect", "Formalization"],
        "answer": "Transformational leadership"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "question": "Which of the following characteristics are contributors to job satisfaction, as identified in Hackman and Oldham’s (1976) influential job characteristics theory?",
        "options": ["Variety.", "Recognition.", "Task identity.", "Task difficulty."],
        "answer": "1, 2 & 3"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "question": "Which of the following are likely to make us find a situation stressful?",
        "options": ["Having knowledge and experience of the job.", "Poor relationships at work.", "Reduced autonomy over work.", "Neurotic temperament."],
        "answer": "2, 3 & 4"
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "question": "One of these statements referring to organizational culture is FALSE – please highlight it:",
        "options": ["Organizational culture can be described as shared values, attitudes and beliefs held by organizational members.", "Pay levels are not a manifestation of organizational culture.", "Organizational psychologists have adopted three approaches to understanding culture.", "We can best understand organizational culture by adopting a multi-dimensional perspective."],
        "answer": "Pay levels are not a manifestation of organizational culture."
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "question": "According to French and Raven’s (1959) five sources of power, which of the following combinations of types and sources of power are correct?",
        "options": ["Legitimate power is wielded by someone whose persuasiveness, popularity or charisma lead others to accede to his/her wishes or suggestions.", "Expert power results from access to knowledge and information, so the computer wizard often gains considerable power in an organization.", "Reward power is the power to force others into action or inaction by the threat of punishment, such as delaying the payment of expenses claims.", "Referent power comes from position in the hierarchy and is imposed by authority."],
        "answer": "Expert power results from access to knowledge and information, so the computer wizard often gains considerable power in an organization."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "question": "Which source of power, according to French and Raven (1959), would be represented by delaying the payment of expense claims or denying requested vacation time to employees?",
        "options": ["Coercive power", "Reward power", "Referent power", "Legitimate power", "Expert power"],
        "answer": "Coercive power"
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "question": "A major area of research on power in organizations examines the experiences of women at work. Which of the statements given below is also true of women at work?",
        "options": ["Stereotyping is no longer a problem for women at work.", "It is illegal to treat pregnancy as a cause for dismissal.", "Women’s representation in the ranks of executives has remained the same in recent years.", "Women tend to use a transactional leadership style."],
        "answer": "It is illegal to treat pregnancy as a cause for dismissal."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "question": "What types of experiences continue to constitute significant problems for women at work?",
        "options": ["Women earn 20% less than men, on the average, for the same work", "Stereotyping of women into “female” jobs", "Women may be dismissed from work if pregnant", "Sexual harassment", "All of the above"],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "question": "Hackman and Oldham (1976) identified which qualities to be most important for job satisfaction?",
        "options": ["Having a variety of tasks to perform", "Feedback about job performance", "Type of leadership", "(a) and (b)", "(a), (b) and (c)"],
        "answer": "(a) and (b)"
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "question": "The shared belief among members of a work team that it is safe to take interpersonal risks and that they will not be rejected or punished for speaking up is referred to as ______________.",
        "options": ["Team process", "Psychological safety", "Team viability", "Groupthink", "Team beliefs"],
        "answer": "Psychological safety"
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "question": "Research has indicated that egocentricity, group polarization and production-blocking all contribute to diminished __________.",
        "options": ["Group decision-making", "Group cohesiveness", "Organizational culture", "Group effectiveness", "Group power"],
        "answer": "Group decision-making"
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "question": "The hierarchical organizational structure of Disneyland, with employees working at varying levels of status including food vendors, street cleaners, ride operators and supervisors, represents what type of organizational culture?",
        "options": ["Integration", "Pluralist", "Fragmentation", "Differentiation", "None of the above"],
        "answer": "Differentiation"
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "question": "What are the psychological effects of unemployment on individuals?",
        "options": ["Depression", "Negative self-esteem", "Anxiety", "Low levels of daily functioning", "All of the above"],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding the psychological effects of unemployment is FALSE?",
        "options": ["The unemployed have poorer mental health than comparable groups of employed people.", "The unemployed have poorer physical health than comparable groups of employed people.", "The psychological effects of unemployment do not usually affect anyone apart from the unemployed person.", "None of the above – all are correct."],
        "answer": "The psychological effects of unemployment do not usually affect anyone apart from the unemployed person."
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "question": "Which one of the following assertions is true? Galton’s notion of the ‘normal distribution’ tells us:",
        "options": [
            "That if your IQ score is anywhere on the distribution, then you are normal.",
            "That as we consider scores increasingly higher or lower than the norm, there will be more and more people registering those scores.",
            "That for any of our ‘natural gifts’ (physical, temperamental or intellectual) there will be an ‘average’ amount of that feature, to which most people approximate.",
            "That most people who complete a university degree will be at the lower end of the distribution."
        ],
        "answer": "That for any of our ‘natural gifts’ (physical, temperamental or intellectual) there will be an ‘average’ amount of that feature, to which most people approximate."
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "question": "Galton introduced the idea of correlation (or co-relation) and showed which of the following to be true?",
        "options": [
            "A correlation of −1 indicates that there is no relationship between the two variables being considered.",
            "Correlations should only be used with variables that are normally distributed.",
            "If variable A (e.g. height) shows a correlation with variable B (e.g. weight) of +1.0, then we know that A caused B.",
            "IQ was correlated with job performance."
        ],
        "answer": "IQ was correlated with job performance."
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "question": "In the early stages of measuring intelligence, which type of intelligence did Spearman identify as the underlying feature that contributes to performance across a variety of different tasks?",
        "options": [
            "Perceptual speed",
            "Individual IQ",
            "Crystallized intelligence",
            "General intelligence (g)",
            "Inductive reasoning"
        ],
        "answer": "General intelligence (g)"
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "question": "Binet was the first psychologist to specify that intelligence tests must be:",
        "options": [
            "Administered and scored in a careful and standardized manner if comparisons between children’s performance are to be valid and reliable.",
            "Presented in the same order to all children and in order of increasing difficulty so that each child can pass as many tests as possible.",
            "Difficult, to ensure that only intelligent people pass them.",
            "Administered in a one-to-one setting and only where the examiner has first established a friendly rapport with the child."
        ],
        "answer": "1,2,4"
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "question": "Which is the case? IQ is calculated as:",
        "options": [
            "The speed at which we process a piece of information.",
            "The ratio of mental age to chronological age.",
            "The number of items you get correct on an intelligence test.",
            "How intelligent you are compared to an adult of the same gender."
        ],
        "answer": "The ratio of mental age to chronological age."
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "question": "Which one of the following is most likely to be true? A person with an IQ of 100 is:",
        "options": [
            "Unlikely to be able to finish high school.",
            "Unable to get a driving licence.",
            "Likely to have trouble completing a university degree.",
            "More intelligent than a person with an IQ of 120."
        ],
        "answer": "Likely to have trouble completing a university degree."
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "question": "Evidence obtained from measures of reaction time, inspection time and physiological changes suggests that general intelligence has a ___________ basis.",
        "options": [
            "Biological",
            "Social",
            "Cognitive",
            "Cultural",
            "Racial"
        ],
        "answer": "Biological"
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "question": "It is generally accepted that there is such a thing as general intelligence. So which of the following statements is true?",
        "options": [
            "Some people have general intelligence, others have multiple intelligences.",
            "The only people who do not have general intelligence are those that have IQs less than 100.",
            "General intelligence develops by adulthood.",
            "General intelligence can be thought of as ‘mental energy’ that is applied to all tasks that we attempt."
        ],
        "answer": "General intelligence can be thought of as ‘mental energy’ that is applied to all tasks that we attempt."
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "question": "All of the following represent intelligences from Gardner’s theory of multiple intelligences except for ___________.",
        "options": [
            "Bodily-kinesthetic",
            "Cultural",
            "Musical",
            "Naturalist",
            "Personal"
        ],
        "answer": "Cultural"
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "question": "Mental retardation is represented by which of the following characteristics?",
        "options": [
            "Low general intelligence",
            "Slow on-line processing",
            "A known organic etiology",
            "IQ below 70",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "question": "Which model assumes that the savant syndrome represents selective brain damage by which some modules were spared whereas others were not?",
        "options": [
            "Sternberg’s triarchic theory",
            "Fluid intelligence",
            "Minimal cognitive architecture",
            "Information-processing",
            "Cognitive components"
        ],
        "answer": "Minimal cognitive architecture"
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "question": "IQ test scores represent __________ measures of intelligence.",
        "options": [
            "Genotypic",
            "Environmental",
            "Modular",
            "Phenotypic",
            "General"
        ],
        "answer": "Phenotypic"
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "question": "By measuring the extent to which identical twins reared together score differently on intelligence tests, researchers can determine the influence of which factors on intelligence?",
        "options": [
            "Shared environments",
            "Non-shared environments",
            "Shared and non-shared environments",
            "Genetic traits",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Non-shared environments"
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "question": "Flynn has shown that there has been a standard deviation increase, per generation, in the mean level of intelligence test performance for most of this century in Western society, which equates to about three IQ points per decade. He believes that such a difference has to be the result of which one of the following?",
        "options": [
            "An environmental change, because gene frequencies in populations couldn't change so quickly.",
            "Improvements in the gene pool as we evolve.",
            "A statistical artefact.",
            "None of the above."
        ],
        "answer": "An environmental change, because gene frequencies in populations couldn't change so quickly."
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "question": "Detterman believes that:",
        "options": [
            "General intelligence represents an average of the processing of several independent components that contribute to the performance of any complex task.",
            "There is a single ability common to all tasks and that differences in this single ability between individuals give rise to differences in ‘general’ intelligence.",
            "There is no such thing as general intelligence",
            "All of the above."
        ],
        "answer": "General intelligence represents an average of the processing of several independent components that contribute to the performance of any complex task."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "question": "Anderson argues three of the following – but which ONE is NOT in line with his arguments?",
        "options": [
            "The first route to knowledge is through thought (central processes).",
            "The ‘thought’ route to knowledge is unrelated to individual differences in IQ.",
            "Thoughtful problem solving can be done either by verbalizing a problem (using language-like propositions to think) or by visualizing it (using visuo-spatial representations to think).",
            "We need two different kinds of knowledge acquisition routines, each generated by one of two specific processors."
        ],
        "answer": "The ‘thought’ route to knowledge is unrelated to individual differences in IQ."
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "question": "The measured difference in IQ between African Americans and white Americans is most likely to be due to which one of the following factors?",
        "options": [
            "Bias in testing.",
            "Genetics.",
            "Environmental differences.",
            "Lack of effort."
        ],
        "answer": "Environmental differences."
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "question": "What explanations have been given to challenge the widely publicized, yet grossly inaccurate, claim that differences in IQ scores between black and white Americans are due to genetic differences in intelligence?",
        "options": [
            "Disadvantaged social groups are treated differently",
            "Socio-economic status provides different opportunities",
            "IQ tests are biased against minority groups",
            "(a), (b) and (c)",
            "No one has challenged the race-IQ claims"
        ],
        "answer": "(a), (b) and (c)"
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "question": "Estimates of heritability for intelligence range between __________.",
        "options": [
            "25% to 35%",
            "50% to 60%",
            "50% to 80%",
            "0% to 100%",
            "40% to 80%"
        ],
        "answer": "50% to 80%"
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "question": "Which are the most widely used individual tests of intelligence?",
        "options": [
            "Wechsler tests",
            "Stanford-Binet tests",
            "IQ tests",
            "Reaction time tests",
            "Spearman’s g"
        ],
        "answer": "Wechsler tests"
    }
];

export default qBank;
